{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sic vita est","incorrectAnswers":["Ad meliora","Amor vincit omnia","Magna est vis consuetudinis"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'Such is life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Which musician released the album '\"Heroes\"'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Kidney","incorrectAnswers":["Liver","Lung","Heart"],"question":"Which vital organ does the adjective renal refer to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"'Flea' is a member of which band?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"We'll always have Paris.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Well, I don’t want to survive. I want to live.\"","\"Just keep swimming.\"","\"I am a golden god!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Casablanca'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Pup","incorrectAnswers":["A Larva","A Farrow","A Joey"],"question":"A young otter is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"McDonalds ","incorrectAnswers":["Burger King","Pizza Hut","KFC"],"question":"Which Chain Of Restaurants Have The Nickname 'The Golden Arches'?'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Their chains","incorrectAnswers":["Their shirts","Their homes","Their families"],"question":"What do the proletarians \"have nothing to lose but\", according to The Communist Manifesto?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Campanulate","incorrectAnswers":["Clochical","Cambarn","Belieux"],"question":"What Word Is Used To Describe Bell Shaped Flowers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The UK","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","New Zealand","South Africa"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of the Dorset and East Devon Coast?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Geri Halliwell","incorrectAnswers":["Mel B","Emma Bunton","Mel C"],"question":"Who was the first Spice Girl to have a solo chart single?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Moon","incorrectAnswers":["Sun","Milky Way","International Space Station"],"question":"The tides on the earth's oceans are actually created by gravitational pull from the ____.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A secretary checks into a remote motel run by a young man under the domination of his mother.","incorrectAnswers":["The story of how the scandal of child molestation within the Boston Catholic church was uncovered.","In a post-apocalyptic wasteland, a woman rebels against a tyrannical ruler.","When a heist goes wrong, the surviving criminals suspect that one of them is a police informant."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Psycho?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sexually transmitted diseases","incorrectAnswers":["Vocal sounds","Grasshoppers and crickets","Ants"],"question":"What is Venereology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Keanu Reeves","incorrectAnswers":["Christian Bale","Gérard Depardieu","Shah Rukh Khan"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Matrix and Speed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"High Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Mannerism","Italian Renaissance","Cubism"],"question":"The painting \"Mona Lisa\" by Leonardo da Vinci is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"St. Louis Blues","incorrectAnswers":["St. Louis Fire","St. Louis Raiders","St. Louis Dynamo"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in St. Louis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Cardigan","incorrectAnswers":["A Turtleneck","A Hoodie","A V-Neck"],"question":"What is the name of the long-sleeve sweater that buttons in front?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malmö","incorrectAnswers":["Barcelona","Vienna","Madrid"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Sweden?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer relased the song 'California King Bed'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Corolla","incorrectAnswers":["Beetle","911","E-Type"],"question":"Which of these models of car is made by Toyota?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cameroon","incorrectAnswers":["United Arab Emirates","Nigeria","Egypt"],"question":"Yaounde is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lord of the Flies","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","Treasure Island","St. Trinian's"],"question":"In which story does the schoolboy \"Piggy\" star?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Emerson, Lake & Palmer","incorrectAnswers":["Supertramp","UB40","Editors"],"question":"Which English progressive rock band released the song 'And did those feet in ancient time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["The United States","Russia","The United Kingdom"],"question":"With the largest amount of assets in the world, in which country is the Industrial & Commercial Bank based?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Coast Redwood","incorrectAnswers":["Mountain Ash","Oak Tree","Douglas Fir"],"question":"What is the tallest tree species in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Disneyland","incorrectAnswers":["Hallmark","Holiday Inn","Airbnb"],"question":"Which brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'The happiest place on earth'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mark Hamill","incorrectAnswers":["Ewan McGregor","Harrison Ford","James Earl Jones"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Luke Skywalker in Star Wars?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Pullman","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Christopher Tolkien","Neil Gaiman"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Amber Spyglass'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Prime Minister","incorrectAnswers":["Chancellor of the Exchequer","Minister for War","Leader of the Opposition"],"question":"What Office Did Churchill Hold For The Longest Continous Period?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nicole Kidman","incorrectAnswers":["Natalie Portman","Kate Winslet","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including Batman Forever and Aquaman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Groke","incorrectAnswers":["Quomodocunquizing","Nudiustertian","Macrosmatic"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'an old Scots term meaning to look at somebody while they’re eating in the hope that they’ll give you some of their food'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Negro","incorrectAnswers":["Nero","Zwart","Azul"],"question":"In Portuguese, what is the word for for 'black'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Jean Paul Sartre","Albert Camus"],"question":"Who wrote \"The count of Monte-Christo\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Igraine","incorrectAnswers":["Gwendolyn","Uther","Morgase"],"question":"What was King Arthur's mother's name?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Alpha","incorrectAnswers":["Apple","Animal","Aeroplan"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter A?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Journey to the Center of the Earth'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Primus","incorrectAnswers":["Metallica","Green Day","Nirvana"],"question":"Which band is responsible for performing the \"South Park\" theme song?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Niger–Congo","Koreanic","Turkic"],"question":"The language 'Northern Kurdish' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Nobody puts Baby in a corner.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"What’s the most you ever lost on a coin toss?\"","\"I am a golden god!\"","\"Toto, I've a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dirty Dancing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Eddie Redmayne","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Carell","Bradley Cooper","Benedict Cumberbatch"],"question":"Who won the 2014 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Stephen Hawking in The Theory of Everything?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mick Fleetwood","incorrectAnswers":["Jimmie Macmillan","Stevie Nicks","Stephen Stills"],"question":"Who Plays Drums For Fleetwood Mac?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dermatitis","incorrectAnswers":["Eczema","Psoriasis","Acne"],"question":"What term is used to describe a number of skin inflammations and is from the Greek word for 'skin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Denmark","Austria"],"question":"Moscow is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Glenn Close","incorrectAnswers":["Kristin Scott Thomas","Naomi Watts","Penélope Cruz"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Guardians of the Galaxy and 101 Dalmatians?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Black Widow","incorrectAnswers":["Gamora","Valkyrie","Captain Marvel"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Scarlett Johansson?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Eritrea","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","North Korea","Lithuania"],"question":"Asmara is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dictator of Nazi Germany.","incorrectAnswers":["One of the pioneers of Quantum mechanics","Roman Emperor who accepted the Christian religion.","Physicist who discovered X-rays."],"question":"Which of the following describes Adolf Hitler?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Amen","incorrectAnswers":["End","Hallelujah","Beyond"],"question":"What is the last word in the New Testament?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Piccolo","incorrectAnswers":["Flute","Clarinet","Bass Flute"],"question":"What is the name of the highest pitched woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["The Ramones","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which band has Bono as its lead singer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Field of Dreams","incorrectAnswers":["Bull Durham","The Natural","Moneyball"],"question":"Which 1989 film features Kevin Costner building a baseball diamond on his corn farm?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Iraq","Ecuador","Thailand"],"question":"In which country would you find the ancient temple complexes of Hampi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Fargo","incorrectAnswers":["12 Years a Slave","Rear Window","A Beautiful Mind"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A car salesman's inept crime falls apart due to his and his henchmen's bungling.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Prague","incorrectAnswers":["Manama","Berlin","Valletta"],"question":"What is the capital city of Czechia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"John Williams","incorrectAnswers":["Hans Zimmer","Ennio Morricone","Danny Elfman"],"question":"Which composer created the music for Star Wars?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The tongue","incorrectAnswers":["The skin","The brain","The heart"],"question":"In French anatomy, what does 'La langue' refer to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Philippines","Malaysia","Cambodia"],"question":"In which country is the city of Shenzhen?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"French president","incorrectAnswers":["French philosopher","French king","French author"],"question":"Who was Charles de Gaulle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Laura Dern","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in both Twin Peaks and Jurassic Park?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","Fleetwood Mac","The Kinks"],"question":"Which band was Robert Plant the lead singer for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Neuf","incorrectAnswers":["Nove","Negen","Trois"],"question":"In French, what is the word for for 'nine'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Toronto Blue Jays","incorrectAnswers":["Toronto Pelicans","Toronto Sporting","Toronto Blues"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Toronto?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sturgeon ","incorrectAnswers":["Salmon","Trout","Herring"],"question":"Which fish does caviar come from? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"weather","incorrectAnswers":["animal diseases","hair and scalp","human beings killing other human beings"],"question":"What is Meteorology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sapientia potentia est","incorrectAnswers":["Hodie mihi, cras tibi","Ego te provoco","Melita, domi adsum"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Wisdom is power'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Treaty of Utrecht","incorrectAnswers":["Treaty of Versailles","Treaty of Yalta","Treaty of Geneva"],"question":"What treaty, signed in 1713, ended the War of the Spanish Succession?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cow","incorrectAnswers":["Pig","Sheep","Goat"],"question":"What animal's meat can a Hindu not eat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Central America","incorrectAnswers":["Brunei","Chile","The Middle East"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Gallo Pinto?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jostein Gaarder","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Jules Verne","J. R. R. Tolkien"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Sophie's World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Austroasiatic","Niger–Congo","Sino-Tibetan"],"question":"The language 'Saraiki' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Bangladesh","Thailand"],"question":"Which country reclaimed about 17% of its land from the sea by pumping out water and making new areas called polders?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Vesuvius","incorrectAnswers":["Etna","Krakatoa","Pelee"],"question":"What volcano destroyed Pompeii?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jean-Jacques Rousseau","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Spinoza","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Man is born free, but is everywhere in chains'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Lions","incorrectAnswers":["The Boro","The Tigers","The Magpies"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Millwall?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Black","incorrectAnswers":["Two","White","Nine"],"question":"What does the word 'noir' mean in French?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Soccer","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","American Football","Sailing"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Copa América?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rojo","incorrectAnswers":["Rouge","Vermelho","Seis"],"question":"In Spanish, what is the word for for 'red'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Fenrir","incorrectAnswers":["Kraken","Goblin","Odin"],"question":"What is the name of the mythical wolf that appears in Norse mythology?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bandar Seri Begawan","incorrectAnswers":["Beirut","Apia","Lilongwe"],"question":"What is the capital city of Brunei?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jackson 5","incorrectAnswers":["The Jackson Brothers","The Smashing Jacksons","Jackson"],"question":"Before going solo, what band was Michael Jackson a member of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chisinau","incorrectAnswers":["Vienna","Cologne","Geneva"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Moldova?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Karel Čapek","incorrectAnswers":["William Gibson","Maurice Leblanc","Neil Gaiman"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Krakatit'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Pup","incorrectAnswers":["A Joey","A Lava","An Owlet"],"question":"A young hamster is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gibraltar","incorrectAnswers":["Rhodes","Athens","Carthage"],"question":"Where was one of the Pillars of Hercules located?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"plant diseases","incorrectAnswers":["flies","schematic layouts","nerves"],"question":"What is Phytopathology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antarctica","incorrectAnswers":["The United Kingdom","The United States of America","Australia"],"question":"Where is Queen Maud Land located?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jimi Hendrix Experience","incorrectAnswers":["The Jimi Hendrix Feeling","Jimi Hendrix and the Artists","Jimi's Boys"],"question":"Which band was Jimi Hendrix a member of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The latissimus dorsi","incorrectAnswers":["The biceps","The triceps","The deltoids"],"question":"Which muscle group is mainly targeted by wide-grip pull-ups that work the muscles of the shoulders and the arms?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Turkish Delight","incorrectAnswers":["Baklava","Börek","Kadayıf"],"question":"What is the traditional Turkish sweet made of gel of starch and sugar, often flavored with rosewater or lemon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Moons of Jupiter'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Who Let the Dogs Out?","incorrectAnswers":["Mickey","We're Not Gonna Take It","Tainted Love"],"question":"Baha Men had a one hit wonder in 2000 with which song?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Valhalla","incorrectAnswers":["Trondheim","Odinsbahn","Asgard"],"question":"What's heaven to fallen Norse warriors?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dubai","incorrectAnswers":["Muscat","Adana","Tel Aviv"],"question":"Which of these cities is in United Arab Emirates?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nosferatu","incorrectAnswers":["Dracula","Frankenstein","The Wolf Man"],"question":"What 1922 F.W. Murnau film is detailed in the movie \"Shadow of the Vampire\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Romania","incorrectAnswers":["Ireland","Netherlands","Estonia"],"question":"Bucharest is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Marine observes the effects of war on his fellow recruits from their boot camp training to fighting in a war.","incorrectAnswers":["A Scottish warrior leads his countrymen in a rebellion to free his homeland.","The jury in a murder trial is frustrated by a member whose caution forces them to consider the evidence.","A car designer and driver battle to build a revolutionary race car."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Full Metal Jacket?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Yaris","incorrectAnswers":["CR-V","911","F-Series"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Toyota?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Alice Springs ","incorrectAnswers":["Perth","Canberra","Wolongonga"],"question":"Which Town Is Situated Close To The Geographic Centre Of Australia","difficulty":"medium"},